# SAI LIKHITH KANUPARTHI

519, 88th Street, Brooklyn, NY • +1 860 620 4718 • sailikhithcse@gmail.com • LinkedIn: sailikhith96 • GitHub: sailikhith7

### **PROFILE SUMMARY**

A self-motivated, skilled master's in computer science student at The New York University. Experienced Software Engineer with a demonstrated history of working in the field of the Software Engineering. Skilled with Algorithms and Data Structures, Data Analysis and visualization, Big Data, Machine Learning, Software Testing Automation and Cloud applications.

### **EDUCATION**

### New York University, Tandon School of Engineering, New York, NY

May 2021

Master of Science, Computer Science | CGPA: 3.22

Relevant Courses: Machine Learning, Algorithm and Data structures Design, Big Data, Computer Networks, Operating Systems

### Jawaharlal Nehru Technological University Anantapur, Andhra Pradesh, India

May 2017

Bachelor of Technology, Electronics and Communication Engineering | GPA: 4.0

Relevant Courses: Python, Linux, Java, C, Mathematics, Probability and Statistical analysis, Linear Algebra, Differential Equations

## **SKILL SET**

Languages: Python (Expert), C/C++ (Expert), Java (Intermediate), PL/SQL(Expert), HTML/CSS(Intermediate), Javascript (Beginner)

Databases: Oracle SQL, MySQL OS: Linux, Windows, Mac Libraries: NumPy, Pandas, Keras, Seaborn, Tensor Flow

Cloud Applications: Oracle SaaS Applications, AWS

Frameworks: Hadoop, Apache Spark

Tools: Selenium Webdriver, Git, Visual Studio Code, Oracle VM, Tableau, Oracle BI, Oracle Data Integrator

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# Oracle India Pt. Ltd (Payroll of Trigent Software Ltd.) | Bangalore, India

Sept 2017 to June 2019

Associate Software Engineer (Java, Python, Oracle SaaS cloud, Data Analysis and Visualization)

- Responsible for developing programs, automation scripts and test cases with 95% success ratio, optimized performance for databases and improved performance significantly by 33.3% i.e., faster processing.
- Researched for the potential issues which client could face after production upgrade and improved production live time 40% faster than expected.
- Helped client boost revenue by 3% and business activity by 20% by playing key role in developing the ERP Dashboard project
  using Business Intelligence data analytics to our client's CEOs, where they can see the gist of their business live.
- Awarded "Golden Partner" as a team for significant contribution in project cost reduction for Indus Towers Limited.

## Bharat Sanchar Nigam Limited | Nellore, India Software Engineer Intern (Python, Oracle SQL, Java, C++)

Dec 2015 to Jan 2016

- Achieved significant improvement in minimizing losses in optical fiber communication channels using data analysis which later helped in troubleshooting the communication channel, thus saving 12% of budget on maintenance.
- Collaborated with hardware engineers in designing an efficient software programs helpful for them to monitor the communication
  equipment health/activity, which improved their work efficiency significantly.

### **SELECTED PROJECTS**

## NYC Open Data - Data Profiling and Analysis (Big Data, Hadoop, PySpark, PL/SQL)

Oct 2019 to Dec 2019

Achieved 3X faster performance in data profiling, semantic analysis and data visualization of the data in NYC Open Data which includes extracting metadata out of unstructured data using Hadoop Distributed File Systems and PySpark.

## Pattern recognition using gesture control (Python, Java, MATLAB)

Apr 2017 to Aug 2017

Implemented a personal remote-controlled research project, where an RC robot is designed using Arduino board, which follows the pattern we gave and detects obstacles on the way using concepts of image recognition and data visualization in it.

## Security Reference Monitor (Python, Pyspark, Linux)

Nov 2019 to Dec 2019

Built a Non-bypassable, Temper-proof security reference monitor on Linux which enforces an access control policy over subjects (e.g., processes and users) ability to perform operations (e.g., read and write) on objects (e.g., files and sockets).

### CERTIFICATIONS

Apache Spark Essentials for Big Data by LinkedIn

Oct 2019

• Oracle Certified Associate Java Programmer (OCAJP) SE8

Dec 2018